# Natalie Boaler

# PRODUCT DESIGNER



East London, E10 6QN Remote/hybrid roles





+447841749682



#### **ABOUT**

Product designer who solves problems with forward thinking, customer focused designs. Over 15 years of creative experience, with a background in fashion, graphics and trend forecasting. A fast paced, multitasking expert, a motivated, positive team player, seeking to bring good energy and innovation to the team.

#### TOOLS

Figma | Adobe | Illustrator | Photoshop | Indesign | Balsamiq | Mockuuups Studio | Usability Hub | Miro | Git | HTML | CSS | Javascript | MS Office Suite |

# **SKILLS**

Competitor Analysis | User and Trend Research | User Personas | Moodboards | User Flows | Wireframing | Usability Testing | I Icon and Logo design | Prototyping | Mockups | Style and Brand Guidelines | Responsive Design |

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Senior Freelance Designer | ASOS**

June 2022 - Present I London

- Produce speed to market, trend focused designs for the ASOS customer across Mens and Womenswear products.
- Weekly customer and competitor analysis, daily trend research, creation of customer boards, trend boards, colour palettes and 100 product designs per month, team collaboration, monthly presentations of final collections and trend direction.
- Continuously creating bestselling products, meeting customer needs with a range of product categories whilst meeting all deadlines.

## Freelance Trend Forecaster | WGSN

September 2022 - Present I London

- Forecast product and consumer trends for the year ahead whilst visually stimulating customers and offering them forward thinking concepts through personalised trend guides and written articles.
- Extensive trend research, creation of digital trend guides, colour palettes and in depth trend focused articles.
- Successfully predicted trends, continuous positive feedback from customers, personalised trend guides increasing from 2 to 4 times yearly.

#### **Senior Freelance Designer**

February 2022 - Present I London

- Keeping a customer portfolio of 5-6 companies, working on a 2-3 projects simultaneously for different brands whilst meeting all deadlines.
- Keep great communication with team members, customer & competitor analysis, trend research, trend boards, colour palettes, branding and product designs, presentation of ideas and concepts.

• Help companies meet deadlines, strengthen collections and increase sales whilst bringing a positive energy to the team.

#### Senior Womenswear Designer | Jack Wills

April 2019 - February 2022 | London

- Created high quality, fashion forward, multi-product designs, with attention to detail and the Jack Wills customer needs.
- Team collaboration, managing and nurturing junior members of the team, customer and competitor analysis, trend research, trend boards, moodboards, colour palettes and product designs. An agile approach to design with many iterations to achieve the final product, presentation of trends and concepts.
- Created new and innovative products which met the customers needs, in turn increasing sales for the business.

### Senior Childrenswear Designer | Juicy Couture

April 2018 - April 2019 | London

#### Senior Menswear Designer | Jack & Jones

October 2014 - April 2018 | Denmark

### Menswear Designer | River Island

August 2012 - October 2014 | London

#### Senior Designer | UCLA

August 2008 - August 2012 | London

## Childrenswear Designer | Cohen & Wilks

July 2006 - September 2007 (year in industry) I Leeds

# **PROJECTS**

#### Slot | Second Hand Clothing App

May - October 2022 | I UI/UX Designer | CareerFoundry Project

• Created a secondhand clothing app, users are able to bid for items at a specified time slot, giving all buyers an equal chance to purchase a product. Conducted analysis across 3 competitors, developed userflows, 14 wireframes, prototypes and mockups using Figma.

### Fast. ∣ Fasting App

July - October 2023 I UI/UX Designer I CareerFoundry Project

• Designed a fasting mobile app, focused on the health benefits of fasting, supporting users to record fasting times and analyse their data. Conducted analysis across 4 competitors, produced a style guide, 12 wireframes, prototypes and mockups for both iOS and Android using Figma. Analysed usability test results and implemented feedback.

## 

October - December 2023 I UI/UX Designer I CareerFoundry Project

• Designed a saving app, to help users save money quickly through saving goals, target spending and saving recommendations. Conducted competitor analysis, created icons and logos using Adobe Illustrator, wireframes, prototypes, mockups and brand guidelines using Figma. Conducted usability tests, adapted designs to incorporate results and further better the product.

# **EDUCATION**

## **CareerFoundry** | **UI Immersion**

April 2022 - December 2023

Intensive 500 hour project-based online training program, with a focus on UI design principles, wireframing, prototyping, mobile app and website design using Figma, user research and testing, UX fundamentals and Frontend Development.

### Leeds University | BA (Hons) Fashion Design (Ind): 2:1,